拯救大兵瑞恩
爸爸
Dad?
（1944年6月6日）
（奧馬哈海灘，綠D區）
別擋住跳板，三十秒後登陸，願主保佑你
Clear the ramp! 30 seconds! May God be with you!
左舷右舷聽著，儘快攻佔炮臺
Port side and starboard side stick!Move fast and clear those mortar holes!
大家儘量分散
I want to see plenty of beach between men.
五個人就容易成為目標，一個人則能躲開
Five men is a juicy opportunity. One man is a waste of ammo.
別讓沙子堵塞槍口，小心行事
Keep the sand out of your weapons! Keep those actions clear!
在灘頭上見
I'll see you on the beach!
避開彈坑，分成左右兩列
Clear the mortar hole! Right and left!
到旁邊去
Over the side!
從左右方下水
Port and starboard!
謝謝
Thank yo...
長官，怎麼辦
What now, sir?
長官，現在怎麼辦
I said, What the hell do we do now, sir?
米勒上尉
Captain Miller! Captain Miller!
米勒上尉     霍瓦特中士
- Captain Miller!   - Sergeant Horvath!
叫你的弟兄攻上灘頭，快
Move your men off the beach! Now!
大家聽我命令，跟著我沖
Okay, you guys, get on my ass! Follow me!
長官，集合點在哪裡     總之不是這裡
- Sir! What's the rallying point?    - Anywhere but here!
怎麼辦，長官     快攻上海堤
- What now, sir?   - The seawall, move up to the seawall!
我要留下來     先攻佔灘頭再說
- Sir, I'm staying!   - Clear the beach to make way.
走出去就死定了
This is all we've got between us and the Almighty.
這灘頭的每一處都被瞄準了
Every inch of this beach has been pre-sighted.
留下來必死無疑
You stay here, you're dead men!
媽媽
Mama, Mama!
伏下來
Stay down, stay down!
你們是什麼部隊     104師的醫療營
- What are you guys?   - 104th Medical Battalion,sir.
我們是來設立醫療站的     丟掉這廢物
- We're here to set up field operations.   - Get rid of that crap!
拿起武器跟我來
Grab yourselves some weapons and follow me.
我中彈了     布格斯
- I'm hit!   - Briggs!
醫護兵
Medic!
天啊，我中彈了     醫護兵
- I'm hit low! God!   - Medic!
我們是海軍搶灘大隊
Navy Beach Battalion, sir!
我得清除這些障礙給坦克開路
I've got to clear these obstacles. Make holes for the tanks!
裝甲車都掉到海裡了     長官，這是命令
- All the armour is floundering at sea.   - Orders, sir!
到別處去，這裡交給我
Go somewhere else! I'm clearing this one.
來吧，布格斯
Come on, Briggs!
醫護兵
Medic!
快走，快
Move, move!
來吧，快
Come on, move!
快走
Move, move!
海岸後勤工作隊裝甲車都無法登岸
Shore party! No armour has made it ashore.
灘頭上都沒有DD坦克，D1缺口還沒打開
We've got no DD tanks on the beach.Dog One is not open!
這裡是誰指揮
Who's in command here?
長官，是你
You are, sir!
霍瓦特中士，你認得這是哪裡嗎
Sergeant Horvath? Do you recognize where we are?
是原定的集合點，但卻沒有支援部隊
Where we're supposed to be, but no one else is.
大家都走散了
Nobody's where they're supposed to be!
海岸後勤工作隊
Shore party!
第一波攻擊無效，無法攻佔海灘
First wave ineffective! We do not hold the beach.
重複，無法攻佔海灘
Say again, we do not hold the beach!
我們都混在一起了，這裡有F、A和G連的弟兄
We're mixed up! We've got people from Fox,Able and George companies.
和海軍爆破隊員及陸戰隊長
Plus, we got some Navy demo guys and a beachmaster.
海岸後勤工作隊
Shore party, Shore party!
指揮官
CAT-F, CAT-F, CA...
萊賓報到     有看到別人嗎
- Reiben here.   - Seen anybody else?
只有傑克森     梅利西報到
- Jackson,but that's it.   - Mellish here!
卡帕佐，德佛裡斯特和韋德在後面
Caparzo! We've got DeForest back there with Wade!
他嚴重失血，韋德說他沒救了
D.'s hurt so bad he's sprung a hundred leaks! Wade says he's used up!
去救其他人吧     我們走吧，他是軍醫
- Move on to somebody you can help.   - Let go, he's a battalion surgeon!
去叫他     韋德
- Get his attention!   - Wade!
韋德     韋德
- Wade!   - Wade!
韋德，別這麼做，太危險了
Wade, don't do it! It's too risky, too risky, Doc!
快滾回來
Get your ass back here!
把他帶回來
Get him off the beach.
我辦到了，我們替他止住血了
I've got it! We've stopped the bleeding!
他媽的
Fuck!
混蛋，趕盡殺絕
Just give us a fucking chance, you son of a bitch!
韋德，走吧     你這個混蛋
- Wade, come on!   - You son of a fucking cocksucker!
韋德，是梅利西，韋德
Wade, it's Mellish. Wade!
走吧，找到米勒了，走吧
Let's move! We found Miller! Let's move!
他媽的
Fuck it!
伏下
Get down, get down!
就只有你們幾個嗎
This is all? This is all that's made it?
我們被分散了，一定還有人的
We got scattered pretty bad. There's bound to be more of us.
這樣不夠
It's not enough.
D1缺口是在右邊還是左邊
Dog One exit. It's the cut to the right, or was it left?
不，維爾維裡在左邊，這裡才是D1缺口
No. Vierville is to the left. This is Dog One.
他們在痛宰我們，根本沒有機會戰鬥，不公平
They're killing us and we don't have a fucking chance! That ain't fair!
收集武器彈藥     收集武器彈藥
- Gather weapons and ammo!   - Gather weapons and ammo!
萊賓，你的手槍呢
Reiben! Where's your BAR?
在水底，差點給敵軍害我被淹死
Bottom of the Channel. The bitch tried to drown me.
再去找一支
Find a replacement.
拿爆破筒出來
Bangalores! Bring out some bangalores!
工兵來了     給我手榴彈
- Engineers coming!   - Grenades, give me grenades!
把爆破筒運到前面去
Bangalores up the line! Bangalores up the line!
小心，爆破筒來了，來吧
Heads up! Bangers coming your way! Come on, come on!
傑克森報到     萊賓回來了
- Jackson here, sir!   - Reiben back, sir.
天啊
Oh, my God!
迫擊炮來了
Mortars incoming!
再給我一支
One more, give me one more!
天啊，痛死我了，我快要死了
Oh, my God, it hurts! I'm going to die!
天啊
Oh, my God! Jesus! Oh, my God!
放進去，繼續
Come on, put it in. Keep it moving.
行了
We've got it.
天啊，這混蛋真幸運
Jesus! Lucky bastard.
快點
Move it! Keep it moving!
你不會死的，別看，沒事的
You're not going to die. You're fine. Just don't look at it. Don't look at it!
用爆破筒來攻擊，讓開
Bangalores! Clear the shingle!
對準沙坑     對準沙坑
- Fire in the hole!   - Fire in the hole!
對準沙坑
Fire in the hole!
可以反攻了，找掩護，到沙坑的另一邊
We're in business! Defilade! Other side of the hole!
給他注射嗎啡
Give him some morphine.
好了，走吧
That's it, let's go.
檢驗過了，注射嗎啡
Inspected, morphine.
一般處理
Routine.
優先處理
Priority.
他死了
He is gone
混蛋，過去
Son of a bitch! Get in there.
可惡，我動不了     梅利西，刺刀給我
- Fuck,I can't move!   - Mellish,give me your bayonet.
中士
Sarge.
兩挺MG-42機槍，兩支迫擊炮
Two MG-42s, two mortars.
在前方20碼，左邊30碼
Add 20, left 30.
那有掩護物，若裝甲車登陸後會是最好的發射位置
There's defilade, but it's a good firing position if we can land the armour.
我們得打開這個缺口
We've got to get this draw open!
萊賓、梅利西，上吧，找到掩護就猛烈開火
Reiben, Mellish! Let's get in the war! Take cover and put fire on that crew.
大衛斯、德伯納多、楊、瓦克，快準備
Davis, DeBernardo, Young, Valk! Get ready!
開火
Covering fire!
去吧
Go, go, go!
敵軍的炮火很厲害
It's a goddam firing squad.
要逃出這裡，只有這樣
It's the only way we can get everybody out of here.
肖特、佩森、麥唐納、帕克斯，你們是下一組
Short, Payton, McDonald, Parkes! You're next!
為什麼不乾脆給我們眼罩不就行了嗎
Why not just hand out blindfolds, Captain?
只能出去拼命，開火
All we can do here is die! Covering fire!
快
Go, go, go!
快點     上，該死
- Come on, come on, come on!  - Go, God damm it!
傑克森     是，長官
- Jackson.   - Sir.
看見那彈坑嗎，在那裡應該能躲開機槍的攻擊
See that impact crater? should give you defilade from the machine gun position.
躲進去好好表現槍法，等我的命令
Get in there and give me some fire discipline. Wait for my command.
去吧
Go!
若你媽看見你這樣會很擔憂的
If your mother saw you do that, she'd be very upset.
我還以為你就是我媽呢
I thought you were my mother.
別遠離我，上帝
Be not Thou far from me, O Lord.
主啊，很抱歉我曾經激怒你
Oh, my God. I am heartily sorry for having offended Thee.
我對此深感懊悔，請聽我的禱告
I detest my sins for having offended Thee, O Lord. Listen to me, Lord.
賜我力量，助我抗敵
All my strength! Haste Thee to help me.
D1缺口打開了，往這邊走
Dog One exit, right here!
大家反攻
We're in business!
快
Move, move!
萊賓     去吧，中士
- Reiben.   - Go, Sarge!
萊賓
Reiben!
來吧，多裡
Come on, Doyle!
中士
Sarge!
多裡，打開噴火器
Flame! Doyle, do it!
別開槍，讓他們吃吃苦頭
Don't shoot! Let them burn!
右邊
On the right!
你們一起死吧，混蛋
I'll give you "comrade", you son of a bitch!
小心，轉過去
Look out! Turn around, turn around.
去幹掉他們
Flush them out!
停火，住手
Cease fire, cease fire! Cut it out, cut it out!
停火
Cease fire!
這是SC第3隊，重複，D1缺口已經打開
Sugar Cane, Sugar Charlie Three. Say again, Dog One is open.
派出推土機，我在這裡等待配合側翼
Send in the dozers. I'm waiting here to tie in my flanks.
什麼
What?
什麼，抱歉，我聽不懂你在說什麼
What? I'm sorry, I can't understand what you're saying!
他說什麼
What did he say, what did he say?
我洗過手準備吃飯了
Look, I washed for supper!
誰有火箭筒，真該死
Who's got a bazooka,Goddammit
笨蛋，你看，是希特勒青年團小刀
Hey, Fish. Look at this, a Hitler Youth knife.
現在是猶太麵包刀了，對吧
And now it's a Shabbat challah cutter, right?
別停下來
Keep it moving!
（義大利、法國、非洲）
好慘烈的景象
That's quite a view.
沒錯
Yes, it is.
很慘烈
Quite a view.
（瑞恩）
“親愛的博伊德先生，你應該已經得悉”
"Dear Mr Brian Boyd. No doubt by now you have received full information"
“你兒子的死訊”
"about the untimely death of your son."
“說什麼也無法減輕您的哀痛”
"No words can ever relieve your grief."
“本部隊對他的死深感惋惜，他是個優秀的士兵”
"Our outfiit has felt his loss greatly... He was a fiine soldier"
“並深信我們所從事的”
"and believed strongly in what we were doing..."
“我們參與了大戰中最重要的軍事行動”
"We were involved in one of the most important operations of the war."
“艾爾使我們能團結一致”
"Al was the one who held us all together."
“他身先士卒”
"He was the first to volunteer."
“那裡有四千人的部隊開過”
"We passed a road where over 4,000 troops had passed."
“尊夫盡忠職守”
"Your husband served in a unit whose duty is to place itself beyond..."
“大家都很懷念他”
"...which we all cherish and hold dear..."
“李等人的死對軍團打擊甚大”
"The loss of Lee and others like him is a distinct blow to the regiment."
“我們瞭解你想知道”
"We understand your desire to learn about"
“他去世時的情形”
"the circumstances leading to his death."
上校，有件事想告訴你
Colonel, I've got something you should know about.
這兩人在諾曼第陣亡
These two men died in Normandy.
這位死于奧哈馬海灘     肖恩·瑞恩
- This one at Omaha Beach.   - "Sean Ryan."
這位死於猶他     彼得·瑞恩
- This man at Utah.   - "Peter Ryan."
這位上周在新幾內亞陣亡
This man was killed last week in New Guinea.
丹尼爾·瑞恩
"Daniel Ryan."
他們是兄弟
The three men're brothers,sir.
他們的媽媽會在下午接到這三封電報
I just learned that this afternoon their mother's going to get all three telegrams.
在搶灘前一晚他們的四弟跟隨101空降師
There's also a fourth brother who parachuted in with 101st Airborne
在諾曼第某處跳傘
the night before the invasion. He is somewhere in Normandy.
他還活著嗎     不知道
- Is he alive?   - We don't know.
跟我來
Come with me.
該死
Goddammit.
四兄弟都在第29師的同一個連隊服役
All four were in the same company in the 29th Division
（陸軍參謀長馬歇爾上將）
但蘇利文兄弟在朱諾送命後我們便分開了他們
but we split them up after the Sullivan brothers died on the Juneau.
能聯絡上四弟詹姆斯嗎
Any contact with the fourth son, James?
不能，他空降在距紐維15裡的內陸，深入了敵區
No. He was dropped 15 miles inland near Neuville, behind German lines.
根本無法知道他空降在哪裡
Mac, there is no way you can know where he was dropped.
據報101空降師的人失散了
First report from lke's people at SHAEF said the 101st is scattered.
諾曼第有很多被空投錯誤的部隊
There are misdrops all over Normandy.
就算瑞恩能安然降落也無法找到他
Assuming Private Ryan even survived the jump, he could be anywhere.
可能他早已陣亡
In fact, he's probably K.I.A.
老實說，若我們派出搜救部隊
And frankly, if we go sending some sort of rescue mission
他們就得穿越德軍固守區
flat hatting throughout German reinforcements along our advance
那一定也會陣亡的
they're going to be K.I.A., too.
這裡有封信
I have a letter here...
是很久以前給波士頓的比克斯比太太的信，聽我讀
...written a long time ago to a Mrs Bixby in Boston. So bear with me.
“女士”
"Dear Madam."
“我已從麻薩諸塞州上將副官的”
"I have been shown in the files of the War Department a statement"
“戰爭部檔案得悉”
"of the Adjutant General of Massachusetts"
“你是五位在沙場上”
'that you are the mother of five..."
“光榮陣亡的戰士的母親”
"...sons who have died gloriously on the field of battle."
“我感到我的言辭薄弱無力”
"I feel how weak and fruitless must be any words of mine"
“根本無法安撫你的悲傷”
"that would attempt to beguile you from the grief"
“也無法彌補你的損失”
"of a loss so overwhelming..."
“但我必須要在此向你致謝”
"...but I can't refrain from tendering the consolation that may be found"
“他們是為了拯救國家而死”
"in the thanks of the republic they died to save."
“願天主安撫你的喪子之痛”
"May our Heavenly Father assuage the anguish of your bereavement"
“讓你永遠懷念遠去的摯愛”
"and leave you only the cherished memory of the loved and lost"
“神聖的榮耀都歸於你們”
"and the solemn pride that must be yours to have laid such a sacrifice"
“因你們為自由付出了重大的代價”
"upon the altar of freedom. Yours very sincerely and respectfully"
“林肯敬上”
"Abraham Lincoln."
那孩子還活著，我們要派人去找他
That boy is alive. We are going to send somebody to find him.
然後帶他遠離戰場
And we are going to get him the hell out of there.
（奧哈馬海灘，登陸後第三天）
後勤官在海灘尋找被炸毀的碉堡
The Quartermaster's up the beach a way. Look for a blown-up bunker.
我是C連的米勒     上尉，請進
- Miller,Charlie Company.   - Go on in,Captain.
若六點以前無法卸下坦克的話
If we don't off-load the Shermans by 06:00
一整師的部隊就會被困在卡倫坦
we'll have a division stuck at Carentan with its pants around its ankles.
再說明一下
Well, you let me know of it.
讓C連死守維爾維裡直到裝甲兵開到
Let Charlie Company hold at Vierville 'til we can get the armour there.
傳令兵
Runner!
原本空降師該打開缺口的
Airborne was supposed to win an open door for us
但他們卻投錯地方
but misdropped
全都失散了，你的情況怎麼樣
and scattered all their sticks into the wind. What's your situation?
第四區攻下了
Yes, sir... Sector Four is secure.
我們摧毀了這幾處的88毫米炮
We took out towed 88s here, here and here.
敵軍有四部坦克和一些運兵車
They got four Shermans and some deuce-and-a-halves.
這兩處的佈雷區很大
These two minefields are actually one big one.
我們到了中心地帶，發現地雷的密度很大
We went up the middle of it, but it turned into a mixed high-density field.
什麼地雷都有，S44型、S42型
A little bit of everything; Sprengmine 44s, Schumne 42s
散片型地雷、A-200，連偵測器都無法找到
pot mines, A-200s, the little wooden bastard the detectors don't pick up.
這裡埋了T43型大地雷
Here, they placed big mushrooms, Teller mine 43s
可能想炸我們的坦克
I guess for our tanks
從這裡到村莊的週邊
from here right up to the edge of the village, right here.
已記下位置，通知了工兵
We marked them and called the engineers.
有遇上反抗嗎     沒想像的那麼強
- Resistance?   - We had higher support expectations.
有一連沒配大炮的346步兵
There was a company without artillery. Wehrmacht. 346th Infantry.
由卡夫加帕指揮，我們俘虜了23人
Von Lucke Kampfgruppe. We ended up with 23 prisoners.
已交由29師的憲兵處置
We turned them over to MPs from the 29th.
我軍的傷亡呢
What about our casualties?
傷亡人數是35死，70人傷
Well, the figure is... We're 35 dead, times two wounded.
他們就是不肯放棄那些重炮
They just didn't want to give up those 88s.
任務很艱巨，所以才找你
It was a tough assignment. That was why you got it.
是，長官
Yes, sir.
約翰
John...
你又有一項任務了     是，長官
- I've got another one for you.   - Yes, sir.
是上級直接交辦的
It's straight from the top.
我希望你和我帶一隊人到紐維去執行公關任務
I wish. You and I are taking a squad to Neuville on a PR mission.
由你帶隊嗎
Oh, are you leading a squad?
一位二等兵死了三兄弟，所以能回家
A private in the 101st lost three brothers and he's got a ticket home.
為何要去紐維呢     他們覺得他在那裡
- Why Neuville?   - They think he's there.
他是被錯投的空降部隊之一
Part of all those Airborne misdrops.
在戰場中找一名士兵很難
It won't be easy finding one soldier in the middle of this goddam war.
就像大海撈針般
Like finding a needle in a stack of needles.
那連上兄弟怎麼辦
What about the company?
最好的跟我們，其他的加入B連
We take the pick of the litter, the rest goes to Baker.
天啊，他們奪走了你的連嗎
Jesus Christ! They took away your company?
部隊是軍方的，我們唯有遵命
It wasn't mine, it was the Army's. So they told me, anyway.
把萊賓、傑克森、韋德、貝斯裡和卡帕佐找來
Get me Reiben on BAR, Jackson, Wade, Beasley and Caparzo.
貝斯裡死了     那找梅利西吧
- Beasley's dead.   - Alright,Mellish then.
有人會法語嗎     據我所知沒有
- Do have a guy who speaks French?   - Not that I know of.
塔爾博特呢     今早死了
- What about Talbot?   - This morning.
我要去找個翻譯員
I'm going to try and dig up another interpreter.
到灘頭的車輛調度場集合
Assemble at the battalion motor pool on the beach.
該怎麼辦     聽著，什麼
- What are we going to do?   - Listen up. What?
我要用大塊乳酪塞進你的屁股
Go home wrapped in the American flag
好讓你棺材蓋國旗回家
with a hunk of cheese in your ass.
我以為你喜歡塞屁股的     什麼
- I thought you liked it in the ass.   - What?
立正
Attention!
稍息，我要找提摩西厄本下士
As you were. I'm looking for Corporal Timothy Upham.
是，我就是厄本
Yes, I'm Upham.
你會說法語和德語吧     是，長官
- Do you speak French and German?   - Yes, sir.
有沒有口音     法語有
- How's your accent?   - Slight one in French.
但德語很純正     很好
- My German's clean.   - Very good.
你已被調派給我了，收拾行囊，我們要到紐維去
You've been re-assigned to me. Grab your gear, we're going to Neuville.
這是什麼時候更新的     今天早上八點半
- When was this updated?   - As of 8:30 this morning.
這是12SS坦克部隊，還有兩隊人向南推進
This is the 12th SS Panzer. These are the two axes advancing south.
紐維有德軍     我知道，下士
- There are Germans in Neuville.   - I understand, Corporal.
紐維有很多德軍     有問題嗎
- There are a lot of Germans in Neuville.   - You've got a problem with that?
我沒作戰過，只懂繪製地圖和翻譯
Please consider that I've never been in combat. I make maps and translate.
我需要會法語和德語的人
I need someone who speaks French and German.
原來的兩位陣亡了     我從新兵訓練後就沒拿過槍
- My two guys were killed.   - I haven't held a weapon since training.
基本訓練時開過槍吧
Did you fire the weapon in Basic training?
開過，長官     那去準備一下
- Yes, sir.   - Well, then get your gear.
長官，我能帶
Sir, may I bring...
能帶打字機嗎
May I bring my typewriter, sir?
知道了，長官
Yes, sir.
謝謝你
Thank you very much.
那是紀念品嗎     不是
- Is that a souvenir?   - No, sir.
慢慢來
Take your time.
下士，凡事都有好的一面
You should look on the bright side of things, Corporal.
是的     還有，這個也沒有用
- Yes.   - For one thing, you don't need those.
但你需要這個     對，要這個
- You'll need that.   - Yes. I'll need this, not that.
你好     你好
- Hey!   - Hey!
你是不是想找死
You want your head blown off?
別再用你的爪子碰我，回去你的崗位
Don't touch me with those rat claws again. Get the fuck back in formation!
我只是想問你來自哪裡
I was just wondering where you're from.
卡帕佐，對吧     滾開，下士
- Caparzo,is it?   - Drop dead,Corporal.
知道了
Gotcha.
每次你向上尉敬禮就會惹來德軍襲擊他
Every time you salute the Captain,you make him a target for the Germans.
對不起     幫幫忙，別那麼做
- I'm sorry.   - Do us a favour.Don't do it.
尤其是當我站在他旁邊時，明白嗎
Especially when I'm standing next to him.Capisci?
明白了     下士，那是什麼書
- Capisco.   - Corporal,what's your book about?
當心你的槍     對不起
- Watch your rifle.   - Sorry.
是關於行軍時發展手足之情的方法
It's about the brotherhood that develops between soldiers during war.
手足之情，你懂什麼是手足之情
Brotherhood? What do you know about brotherhood?
要注意這傢伙
Get a load of this guy, Fish.
你為什麼不去問上尉是哪裡人呢
Why don't you ask the Captain where he's from?
去問他，他什麼都會告訴你的
Ask the Captain. He'll tell you everything you want to know about him.
解釋給我聽
Explain the maths of this to me.
八個人為什麼要冒險救一個人呢
Where is the sense in risking the lives of the eight of us to save one guy?
20度，有人想回答這個問題嗎
20 degrees. Anybody wants to answer that?
萊賓，想想那可憐蟲的媽媽吧
Reiben, think about the poor bastard's mother.
醫護兵，我也有媽媽
Hey, Doc, I've got a mother.
你有媽媽，中士也有媽媽
You've got a mother, Sarge has got a mother.
我敢說上尉也有媽媽
Shit, I bet even the Captain's got a mother.
也許上尉沒有，但我們全都有
Maybe not the Captain, but the rest of us.
“不問原因，只求為國犧牲”
"Their's is not to reason why their's is but to do and die"
下士，那是什麼意思
What the fuck is that supposed to mean, Corporal?
我們都該死嗎
We're all supposed to die?
厄本說的是我們的職責     是，長官
- Upham's talking about our duty.   - Yes, sir.
我們全都得服從命令
We all have orders to follow.
是的，長官，謝謝    就算任務是“苦差”也要嗎
Yes, sir. Thank you. Even if the mission is "FUBAR"?
這才更加要服從
Especially if the mission is "FUBAR".
“苦差”是什麼     那是德語
- What's "FUBAR"?   - It's German.
沒聽過
Never heard of that...
長官，我對此有點意見
Sir, I have an opinion on this matter.
說出來聽聽吧
By all means, share it with the squad.
我的想法是
From my way of thinking
這次任務浪費了寶貴的軍事資源
this mission is a misallocation of valuable military resources.
是嗎，繼續
Yeah? Go on.
我覺得上帝賜給我打仗的天分
It seems to me that God gave me a sepcial gift made me a fine instrument of warfare.
萊賓，聽好，這樣抱怨才對，繼續，傑克森
Reiben,pay attention.Now, this is the way to gripe.Continue,Jackson.
要是他派我這個狙擊手
If He was to put me and this sniper rifle anywhere up to and including
到希特勒一裡範圍內
one mile of Adolf Hitler with a clear line of sight, sir...
大家就能收拾行囊回家，戰爭就結束了，阿門
Pack your bags, fellas, the war is over. Amen.
鄉巴佬，這主意不錯
That's brilliant, bumpkin.
上尉，你呢，你不會抱怨嗎
What about you, Captain? You don't gripe at all?
我是上尉，身負重任，不會向你抱怨
I don't gripe to you. I'm a captain. There's a chain of command.
上級永遠是發牢騷的物件
Gripe always go up.
你向我發牢騷，我向我上級發牢騷，如此類推
You gripe to me, I gripe to my superior officers, and so on.
我不會在你面前發牢騷，你是突擊隊員，應該明白
I don't gripe in front of you. You should know that as a Ranger.
對不起，就當你不是上尉或我是少校吧
I'm sorry, but let's say that you weren't a captain or that I was a major.
你會說什麼
What would you say?
那樣我就會說，這項任務棒極了
In that case, I'd say, "This is an excellent mission"
意義重大，值得我全力以赴
"with a valuable objective worthy of my best efforts."
而且我對瑞恩的母親感到深切的悲痛
"Moreover, I feel heartfelt sorrow for the mother of Private Ryan"
為了慰藉她，我願意賠上我與部下的性命
"and I'll lay down my life and those of my men, especially yours, Reiben"
尤其是你，萊賓
"to ease her suffering."
他很棒     我喜歡他
- He's good.   - I love him.
算了
Fine!
打雷     閃電
- Thunder!   - Flash!
厄本，到那邊去，萊賓，你們四個過去
Upham, over there. Reiben, you four go.
去吧
Go, go, go, go!
很高興看見你     希爾中士，救星來了
- You are a sight for sore eyes.   - Sergeant Hill, our reliefs showed up.
有多少人     八個，但不是救兵
- How many are you?   - Eight. We're not your relief.
為什麼     我們來找二等兵瑞恩
- What do you mean, sir?   - We're here for a Private Ryan.
誰     瑞恩，為什麼
- Who?   - Ryan? What for?
他在這裡嗎     大概在鎮的另一邊
- Is he here?   - Maybe on the other side of the town.
周圍都有德軍，很難通過
It's hard to get to. The Germans punched a hole in our centre.
我軍給德軍切斷，他叫什麼名字
- They cut us right in two.   - What's his name,again?
瑞恩，詹姆斯·瑞恩，隸屬101空降師
Ryan, James Ryan. He dropped in with the 101st.
高德曼，找傳令兵來     傳令兵
- Goldman, get me a runner!   - Runner!
來吧
Come on!
鐘斯，讓開
Jonesy, make a hole up there!
我們被東面的炮火所阻
We got stopped by fire from the eastward.
德軍聚集了兩個團的兵力
The Germans have been reinforcing two regiments all day.
已經有四十五分鐘沒有動靜
It's been quiet for 45 minutes.
德軍正把火力集中於西面
The Germans concentrate their fire westward.
誰在廣播     達伍德·迪·撒多夫
- Who's that on the loudspeaker?   - Dagwood Duesseldorf.
他在替德軍激勵士氣
Our friendly neighbourhood morale officer.
“自由神像完蛋了”
"The Statue of Liberty is kaput."
想擾亂我們軍心
That's disconcerting.
笨蛋，你父親的包皮已被割掉了
Your father was circumcised by my rabbi, you prick!
開槍掩護
Cover!
去吧
Go!
去你的臭混蛋     伏下
- You sadistic fucking animals!   - Get down.
敵人知道我軍通訊中斷，所以針對傳令兵
They know we're not in direct contact. They'll single out the runners.
為什麼要射殺他們
Why do they shoot them up?
不能留活口，以防軍情外泄，我們也會這樣做
As long as his lungs are working, he carries the message. We'd do the same.
不，我們不會     韋德，準備起程
- No, we wouldn't!   - Wade! Get them ready to travel.
博伊德     來吧
- Boyd!   - Come on!
再試一遍，設法通知漢米爾上尉我們正趕過去
Try again! Let Captain Hamill know we're coming.
紐維其他地方怎麼樣
What's the rest of Neuville like?
接著會看到兩層建築物，有很多窗戶
The next block's got two-storey buildings. A lot of windows.
有一廣場可作藏身之用
There's a square with good cover.
帶我去，中士，留在這裡
Show me. Sarge, hold right here!
是，長官
Yes, sir!
別在這裡挨打，到裡面躲避
Stay out of this enfilade and use the buildings.
到左邊去，邊走邊射擊，我們各派兩人
Try a left hook. Shoot and scoot. Two of yours, two of mine.
黑斯亭斯、高德曼，到前面去
Hastings, Goldman! Up front!
萊賓、卡帕佐     通訊仍受敵軍干擾
- Reiben, Caparzo.   - They're still jamming us.
儘快到角落去，小心行事
Short runs, high and low at the corners. It's going to be tight.
準備進行近身戰，去吧
Be prepared for close contact. Go.
厄本，跟霍瓦特中士待在一起
Upham! You stay with Sergeant Horvath.
上尉，我會像內褲般粘著他
Stay here! I'll wear him like underwear, Captain. You stay with me.
廣場閘口在大樓的盡頭
Past the end of the block are the gates of the square.
好     好的
- Good.   - Alright.
萊賓，上尉從哪裡來的
Reiben, where's the Captain from?
猜中的話有獎     獎金三百塊
- If you figure it out, you'll get a prize.   - 300 bucks, last I heard.
大家下注，最少五塊
The company's got a pool. Five bucks gets you in.
就在拐彎處，躲到閘門後面去
It's around this corner. Defilade right up to those gates.
一定有人知道他來自哪裡
Somebody must know where he's from.
我跟他一起那麼久也毫無頭緒
I've been with him since Casserene Pass. I don't have a clue.
我的腳踝很痛，戰爭沒結束已經要坐輪椅
My ankles are killing me. I'll need a wheelchair before the war is over.
老天，就跟老婦一樣
That's it! Oh, my God! That ankle is like an old woman.
就像，老天
Like an old... Oh, God!
萊賓，你連他上哪所學校也不知道嗎
Reiben. So you don't even know where he went to school?
他沒念書，是軍部用大兵屍體組裝而成
He didn't go to school. They assembled him at OCS out of dead Gls.
我知道他的來歷
Pay attention to detail. I know where he's from and what he did
因為我看得仔細
because I pay attention to detail.
厄本，別信他的鬼話
Hey, Upham! Careful you don't step in the bullshit.
說吧     打雷
- Do it.   - Thunder!
打雷，不然開火
Thunder, or we will fire on you!
梅利西、卡帕佐，過來
Mellish, Caparzo, come here!
叫他們表明身分
Tell them to show themselves.
問問德軍在哪裡
Ask them where the Germans are.
他說什麼     關於孩子的
- What is he saying?   - Something about the children.
孩子     他想我們帶走孩子
- Kids?   - He wants us to take them.
不行，不能帶走孩子
No, no. We can't take the kids.
不可以，不行
We can't take the kids! No, no!
他們以為這樣較安全     才不會
- They think they'll be safe.   - They won't be safe with us!
你瘋了嗎，聽從上尉的命令
Are you nuts? Listen to the Captain!
他們以為孩子會安全一點
They think they'll be safe with us.
什麼地方也不會安全，卡帕佐，交回孩子
It's not safe anywhere. Caparzo! Put that kid back!
卡帕佐，把孩子還給他們     請放心
- Caparzo, put the girl back!   - It's OK, it's OK.
交回孩子
Give that kid back!
厄本，怎麼說請放心     她讓我想起外甥女
- Upham, how do you say, "It's OK?" I can't.   - She reminds me of my niece.
把孩子交回去
Get the kid back up there!
最少也該把她帶到下個市鎮
We should at least take her to the next town.
我們有任務在身，不是來救孩子
We're not here to do that, we're here to follow orders!
中士，把孩子接過來
Sarge, take this goddam kid!
躲好
Cover, cover!
糟糕
No!
可惡，哪裡射過來的
Goddammit! Where did that come from?
聽到槍聲前他已倒地
He was on the ground before we heard the shot.
是我就會到那裡
That's where I'd be.
我看不到     450碼外，也許在陰暗處
- I didn't see it.   - 450 yards, maybe a shade under.
大家別冒險出去，那槍手槍法很厲害
I wouldn't venture out there, fellas. This sniper's got talent!
別哭，我帶你找爸媽
Please don't cry. I'll take you back to Mama and Papa. Please don't cry.
來吧
Come on.
卡帕佐
Carpy!
上尉     撐著，卡帕佐
- Captain!   - Hold on, Caparzo.
扶我起來，我可以走路
Help me up. I can walk.
卡帕佐，別動
Caparzo, stay still!
兩格，風向偏左
Two clicks. Left wind.
笨蛋
Fish!
上尉，看到他嗎，他怎麼了
Captain, can you see him? How is he?
韋德，別亂來
Wade, you stay put.
上尉，他哪裡中槍
Where is he shot, Captain?
看得到他嗎     別出去
- Can you see him?   - You stay there!
可惡，躺下來
Damn it! Stay down!
你怎麼了，你中了槍要我照顧嗎
What's the matter with you? Am I going to take care of you if you get hit?
笨蛋，過來
Fish, come over here!
卡帕佐，躺下來別動
Carpy, put your head down! Why can't you put your head down?
神啊，我信靠你
Oh, my God, I trust in Thee.
別讓我蒙羞，別讓敵人戰勝我
Let me not be ashamed. Let not my enemies triumph over me.
抄下來，替我寄出去
Copy it. Copy it and send it for me.
放下來，你自己寄
You're going to send it yourself. Put it down!
信沾了血     我知道
- It's got blood on it!   - I see it.
給我爸的，沾了血，笨蛋
It's... It's to my dad. It's got blood on it, Fish.
打中了，伏下
We got him. Stay down.
傷得很重嗎     胸口中彈，或許肺被打中了
- How bad is it?   - Chest, maybe lung shot.
把那台30毫米大炮放到街上
Get that.30 up the street!
報告情況     上面安全
- Detail!   - Clear, up!
下面安全
Clear, down!
早就說過不能帶孩子
That's why we can't take children.
霍瓦特中士，檢查武器
Sergeant Horvath, do an ammo check.
厄本，把水壺裝滿
Upham, canteens. Fill them up.
希爾中士     是的，長官
- Sergeant Hill.   - Yes, sir.
召集弟兄，在廣場西北角集合
Gather your men. We'll form up at the northwest corner of the square.
傑克森     是，長官
- Jackson.   - Sir!
梅利西，去檢查那座塔，儘快回來，快去吧
Mellish. Check the tower, hustle back here. Right now, go!
該死的瑞恩
Fuck Ryan!
打雷     閃電，進來吧
- Thunder!    - Flash! Come on in!
我們在找漢米爾上尉
Hey, guys. We're looking for Captain Hamill.
那邊，過了廣場就到     過了廣場
- Down there, across the square.   - Across the square.
慢慢走，提防狙擊手
Go easy. Watch for snipers.
請坐
Sit down.
吉米，叫漢米爾上尉過來
Jimmy T. Go and find Captain Hamill. Bring him here.
什麼，上面嗎     我怎麼知道，自己去找
- What? Up there?   - How should I know? Go and look!
謝謝你，混蛋
Thank you, you moron.
先在這裡休息一下
Alright. You guys just flake out here for a while.
我要把石子倒出來
Let me get this goddam hitchhiker out of my boot.
放下武器     立刻放下
- Put your weapons down!   - Drop them now!
我會開槍的
I'll shoot you!
放下武器
Drop, drop 'em!
立刻放下武器
Put 'em down!
上面安全了
Clear, up!
該死
Shit, shit!
上面安全了
Clear, up!
下面也安全了
Clear, down!
這樣子夠讓人變老了
Enough to make you old.
但願如此
Let's hope so.
101師前導部隊的漢米爾     第二突擊隊的米勒
- Hamill, Pathfinders 101st.   - Miller, 2nd Rangers.
謝謝
Thank you.
我們在找二等兵瑞恩，他是你的屬下
We're looking for a Private Ryan. He's part of your outfit.
有可能找到他嗎
Any chance that you policed him up?
路上的情況怎麼樣     景色優美，彈藥快用光了
- How was the road in?   - Scenic. We lost most of our ammo.
還死了一位隊員
Not to mention one of our men.
中尉，把火箭筒調換到右邊的路旁
Lieutenant! Redeploy that bazooka to the right side of the road.
去找瑞恩過來
And get Ryan up here!
瑞恩，到前面來
Ryan! Ryan! Front and centre! Ryan!
那傢伙來了
Here comes our boy.
我早說他是個混蛋
I told you he was an asshole.
二等兵瑞恩報到     稍息
- Private Ryan reporting as ordered.   - At ease.
第二突擊隊的米勒上尉有話跟你說
Captain Miller, 2nd Rangers, wants a word with you.
這邊來
This way.
請坐下
Alright. Take a knee.
二等兵，有個壞消息要告訴你
Private, I'm afraid I have some bad news for you.
這真是讓人難以啟齒
Well, there isn't any really easy way to say this, so...
我就直說吧，你的兄弟死了
...so I'll just say it. Your brothers are dead.
我們奉命來找你
We have orders to come and get you...
因為你可以回家了
...because you're going home.
天啊，我兄弟死了
Oh, my God! My brothers are dead!
我本想帶他們去釣魚的
I was going to take them fishing when we got home.
對不起，詹姆斯，真是不知該說什麼
I'm so sorry, James. I can't tell you how much.
他們是怎樣死的     陣亡
- How did they die?   - They were killed in action.
沒有可能
That can't be.
他們還在念中學
They can't be my brothers. They're still in grammar school.
你是詹姆斯·瑞恩嗎     是的
- You're James Ryan?   - Yeah.
愛阿華州的詹姆斯·法蘭西斯·瑞恩
James Francis Ryan from lowa?
我是明尼蘇達州的詹姆斯·腓德利克·瑞恩
James Frederick Ryan, Minnesota.
那表示我弟弟沒事嗎     對，我確信他們很好
- Does that mean my brothers are OK?   - Yeah,I'm sure they're fine.
你能肯定嗎     我們找的不是這個瑞恩
- Are you sure?   - We're looking for a different Ryan.
只是一場誤會而已
It's just a big foul-up.
你怎麼能確定，怎麼知道是不是又弄錯了
How can you be sure? How do you know that the foul-up isn't
原來是他的弟弟沒事，而我
that his brothers are OK, and...
中尉     麻煩你了，很抱歉
- Lieutenant.   - I'm sorry for the trouble.
我在離開前才剛給他們寫信，我要回家
I just wrote them a letter before I left. I've got to get home.
我要立刻回家，我想回家
I've got to get home right now. I want to go home.
我們的瑞恩在哪裡呢     不知道
- Where is our Ryan?   - Don't know.
可以跟指揮官聯絡一下嗎     瑞恩隸屬於什麼單位
- Are you in touch with your CO?   - What unit's Ryan in?
506團的B連     那個斷腳的傢伙是506團的
- Baker Company, 506th.   - The guy with the broken foot's in 506th.
我猜是C連吧     你猜
- Charlie, I think.   - You think?
瑞恩，我不知道，天啊
Ryan? Don't know... Man!
你們在哪裡降落     維爾維裡
- Where was your dropzone?   - Vierville.
維爾維裡，那怎麼會到這來的
Vierville? How did you end up here?
說來話長，C-47受到猛烈的攻擊
You got me, sir. The C-47 took heavy fire.
機師拼命閃避炮火
Pilot went crazy turning every which way.
跳傘時炮火更猛，情況混亂，我就來了這裡
We took more fire in the drop. It got messy. I ended up here.
我沒見過我的隊友，天知道他們在哪裡
I haven't seen a single guy from my stick. God knows where they are.
有B連的人談到空降區在哪嗎
Did anybody from Baker Company talk about where the dropzone was?
沒有，但大家的集合點一樣
No, but they had the same rallying point as us.
指出來
Show me.
我們很累，在這裡休息三小時，入夜後出發
My men are beat. We'll hold up here for three hours and pull out after dark.
這鎮上有三星級飯店什麼的嗎
Got anything left in this town, like a three-star hotel?
有乾淨的床單、枕頭和客房服務嗎
Something with clean sheets, soft pillows and room service?
舒適的教堂怎麼樣     也好
- How about a nice, comfy church?   - We'll take that.
有什麼消息，戰況怎麼樣
What have you heard? How is it all falling together?
我們攻下了灘頭堡，但蒙蒂卻慢條斯理的進軍康城
We got the beachhead secured,but Monty's taking his time moving on Caen.
要他準備好我們才能撤軍     大家高估他了
- We can't pull out'til he's ready,so...   - That guy's overrated.
我同意     要拿下康城才能攻下聖羅
- No argument here.   - You take Caen to take Saint-L8.
要攻下瓦隆尼先要拿下聖羅     瓦隆尼之後是瑟堡
- You gotta take St-L8 to take Valognes.   - Valognes,you've got Cherbourg.
瑟堡之後是巴黎     最後是柏林
- Cherbourg,you've got Paris.   - Paris,you've got Berlin.
然後就能坐大船回家
And then that big boat home.
你在這裡能幫到我很多，但我瞭解你的任務
I could really use you around here, but I understand what you're doing.
是嗎     我也有幾個兄弟
- You do?   - I've got a couple of brothers myself.
原來是這樣     祝你好運
- Oh.   - Good luck.
謝謝     不，我是說真的
- Thank you.   - No, I mean it.
找到他，帶他回家
Find him. Get him home.
你的手怎麼了
What's with your hand?
不知道
I don't know.
在樸資茅斯上船後就是這樣
It started in Portsmouth when we went down for embarkation.
偶爾會這樣     你該找別的工作
- It comes and goes.   - You have to find yourself a new job.
這工作不適合你了
This one doesn't seem to agree with you any more.
什麼事
What?
什麼     沒什麼
- What?   - Nothing.
在安濟奧那小子叫什麼名字
What was the name of that kid at Anzio?
用手倒立走路那個
The one who walked on his hands
唱著空中飛人之歌那個嗎
and was singing that song about the man on the flying trapeze?
是維馳奧     維馳奧
- Vecchio.   - Vecchio!
對，他是個笨蛋
Yeah, Vecchio. He was a goofy kid.
喜歡在別人的外套上尿出一個“V”字，代表維馳奧
I remember he used to pee a "v" on everybody's jackets. For "vecchio".
代表勝利     維馳奧
- For victory.   - Vecchio.
他長得很矮     他是侏儒吧
- He was so short.   - He was a midget, wasn't he?
那他怎麼能當上突擊隊隊員的
Yeah, how did he get to be a Ranger?
他的腳被打斷了，所以用手走路
He got shot in the foot once, walking on his hands.
走得很快
He could walk faster on his hands.
跑得更加快
He could run faster on his hands.
維馳奧
Vecchio. Yeah.
卡帕佐
Caparzo.
每當一位弟兄死去
You see, when you end up killing one of your men
就要告訴自己，這樣能拯救
you tell yourself it happened so you could save the lives of
二、三、四或十條人命
two, three, or ten others.
甚至是一百人
Maybe 100 others.
你知道我當指揮時有多少部下陣亡嗎
Do you know how many men I've lost under my command?
多少     九十四個
- How many?   - 94.
但那代表我救了十倍那麼多的人嗎
But that means I've saved the lives of ten times that many, doesn't it?
甚至是二十倍
Maybe even 20, right? 20 times as many?
事情就是這麼簡單
And that's how simple it is.
就是這樣把任務與屬下之間
That's how you rationalise making the choice
所做的選擇合理化
between the mission and the men.
但這次任務正是救人
Except that this time the mission is a man.
這個瑞恩最好值得我們去救
This Ryan had better be worth it.
他回家後最好能行醫救人
He'd better go home and cure some disease
或是發明長壽燈泡
or invent a longer-lasting light-bulb or something.
我想十個瑞恩也抵不了一個卡帕佐或維馳奧
For the truth is that I wouldn't trade ten Ryans for one Vecchio or Caparzo.
阿門
Amen.
你看，又來了     長官
- Look, there it goes again.   - Sir.
還好吧
Are you alright?
兩小時後出發，小睡一會吧
We'll move out in two hours. Why don't you get some sleep?
不知道他怎麼能做到的     什麼
- I don't know how he does it.   - What's that?
如此熟睡，你看
Falls asleep like that. Look at him.
他躺下就睡著了
The guy's lights-out the minute his head hits the pack.
因為問心無愧     有句話怎麼說
- Clear conscience.   - What's that saying?
神與我們同在，那誰與敵軍同在
God's on our side, who could be on theirs?
若神與我們同在，誰會是我們的對手
"If God be for us, who could be against us?"
不錯，我說了什麼
Yeah, what did I say?
想睡著的話保持清醒就行了
The trick to falling asleep is trying to stay awake.
為什麼，韋德
How is that, Wade?
我媽當實習醫師時習慣在夜間工作
When my mother was an intern she used to work through the night
白天睡覺
and sleep through the day.
只有她回家我們才能聊天
The only time we talked was when she'd get home.
我總會躺著，儘量保持清醒，但從沒成功過
I used to lie in bed and stay awake as long as I could,but it never worked
我越不想睡就越快睡著
because the harder I tried the faster I'd fall asleep.
但在家裡沒關係，因為媽會回家
That wouldn't have mattered in my house.Ma would've come home,
把我弄醒，聊到天亮，聊天時她總是不知道累
shook me awake,chatted me up 'til dawn.She was never too tired to talk.
也許她在那個時候才有機會說話
That's probably the only time she could get a word in.
有趣的是有時她下班時間早了
Funny thing is,sometimes she would come home early
我會假裝睡著了
and I'd pretend to be asleep.
誰，你媽嗎     對
- Who, your mum?   - Yeah.
她會站在門口看著我
She'd stand in the doorway looking at me,
我就閉眼裝睡
and I would just keep my eyes shut.
我知道她特地早些回來
And I knew that she just wanted to find out about my day,
跟我聊天，問我那天過得怎麼樣
that she came home early just to talk to me.
但我卻仍然不動，假裝已經熟睡
And I still wouldn't move. I'd still pretend to be asleep.
我也不知道為什麼會那樣做
I don't know why I did that.
只有幾個小時，閉嘴睡覺吧
We've only got a couple of hours. Shut up and go to sleep.
上尉，長官
Captain? Sir?
下士
Corporal.
你怎麼了，沒事吧
How are you doing? Are you alright?
還好，我想這一切對我有益
Yeah, I think this is all good for me, sir.
真的嗎，為什麼
Really? How is that?
“戰爭能訓練判斷力，磨練意志”
'War educates the senses, calls into action the will,"
“增強體格”
"perfects the physical constitution,"
“人在生死關頭的瞬間”
"brings men in such swift and close collision in critical moments"
“強弱立判”
"that man measures man."
愛默森也許是這樣讓自己積極起來的
I guess that's Emerson's way of finding the bright side.
你也有讀愛默森啊     一點點
- You know Emerson, sir?   - I know some.
上尉，你來自哪裡，在戰前你是做什麼的
So, where are you from, Captain? What did you do before the war?
賭金有多少了
What's the pool up to?
大概是三百塊吧
I think it's around 300, sir.
等到了五百的時候我就把答案告訴你，平分賭金
When it gets up to 500,I'll give you the answer and we'll split the money.
你覺得怎麼樣
How about that?
要是你這麼想我就有責任建議你
If that's the way you feel, I feel it's my duty under your command
等賭金累積到一千塊
to suggest that we wait until it gets up to 1,000. I think it's...
要是活不了那麼久呢，怎麼辦
What if we don't live that long?
五百     五百也不錯
- 500?   - 500 would be good, yes.
好的，長官
Yes, sir.
睡吧，下士     是，長官
- Get some sleep, Corporal.   - Yes, sir.
誰有磺胺粉
Who's got sulfa powder?
醫護兵，我弟兄在流血，需要止血帶
Medic, my buddy's bleeding! He needs a tourniquet.
韋德     什麼事
- Wade.   - Yes, sir?
去幫他一下     是
- See what you can do.   - Yes, sir.
堅持住，很快就有人來救你
Hold on, fellas. It won't be much longer.
情況怎麼樣
How are we doing here?
沒事的，別擔心，醫師來了
Alright. You're doing alright, don't worry about it. The Doc's in town.
放心，29步兵團已突圍，很快到這裡
Don't worry. The 29th Infantry's breaking through. They'll be here soon.
誰有血漿
Has anybody got plasma?
上尉
Hey, Captain!
有什麼消息嗎     我是德溫得中尉
- Soldier,you want to fill me in?   - Yeah.Lieutenant DeWindt.
隸屬於第99運兵中隊，負責運載300與307滑翔機步兵
99th Troop Carrier Squadron carrying in 300th and 307th Glider Infantry.
我是飛行員     二等兵
- This one was mine. I was the pilot.   - Private!
22人陣亡     來照顧他
- 22 men dead.   - Take care of this one.
我著陸時沒受一點傷，副駕駛卻死了
I landed there without a scratch, took my co-pilot's head right off.
這些人是誰
Who are these people?
我們載的士兵第一晚就離開，之後沒再見過他們
The guys we came in with headed off the first night. Haven't seen them since.
期間別的士兵三五成群地陸續出現
In the meantime other guys keep showing up. One, two, six at a time.
然後有軍官來把散兵湊成部隊
Then some officer will come along, patch together a mixed unit
再次出發作戰
and head off to make trouble.
我們在找101師506B連的二等兵瑞恩
We're looking for a Private Ryan, Baker Company, 506th of the 101st.
這可難倒我了，這裡人來人往
You got me. A lot of guys come in and out.
厄本，到那隊人裡面找瑞恩
Upham! Check out that squad. See if Ryan's in it.
是的，長官
Yes, sir.
萊賓，聞聞他的腿像不像臭乳酪
Reiben! Smell that leg, right there. Find out if it's south of cheese.
什麼
What?
雙手放頭上
Hands over your head.
別停下來
Keep moving!
我是猶太人
I'm Jude, you know.
無法把他弄出來，我需要一台絞車
I couldn't pry him out of there. I need a winch.
是的
Yeah.
是星級軍官     是的
- Stars.   - Yeah.
阿門準將，101空降師的副指揮官
Brigadier General Amend. Deputy Commander, 101st.
有些天才提議在機艙焊接鋼板
Some genius had the great idea of welding steel plates onto our deck
以免地面的炮火傷到上將
to keep the General safe from ground fire,
但他們到空降前才告訴我們
but they forgot to tell me until just before we were getting airborne.
就像開貨運列車飛行般嗎
That's like trying to fly a freight train. OK?
負荷過重，地面炮火又猛烈
Gross overload. Trim characteristics all shot to hell.
我為了保持平衡手幾乎都弄斷了
I nearly broke both my arms trying to keep her level.
脫勾時我已經盡力了
When we released I cut as hard as I could,
嘗試保持高度，以免失速
trying to gain some altitude and keep her from stalling.
最後像隕石一樣掉下來，結果變成這樣
We came down like a fucking meteor. And this is how we ended up.
其他飛機總算順利著陸
The others stopped easy enough, though.
我們的飛機太重了
We were just too damn heavy, you know?
草地濕滑，而且是下坡
The grass was wet. Downward slope and all.
死了二十二人
22 guys dead.
全為了一個上將嗎     一個人
- All that for a general?   - One man.
這種事經常發生     “苦差”
- There's a lot of that going around.   - "FUBAR."
“苦差”     “苦差”
- "FUBAR."   - "FUBAR."
“苦差”     都說對了
- "FUBAR."   - You all got that right.
我在德語字典中查不到“苦差”
I looked it up in a German dictionary. "FUBAR"'s not there.
厄本，那邊也有傘兵
Upham! There are more paratroopers out there.
去找瑞恩
Find out if one of them is Ryan.
你在這裡找找看
You might want to check this out, sir.
是兵籍牌，多得數不完
Dog tags. More than I really want to count, sir.
我已蓋過許多屍體
I've covered a lot of bodies, sir.
傑克森，從這些開始找吧     是
- Jackson. Start going through those.   - Yes, sir.
我來幫忙
I'll help.
你覺得有那小子嗎     如果有我會找到的
- Do you think that little prick's in there?   - If he is,I'm going to find him.
我敢說那混蛋     我打賭他還活著
- I bet that son of a bitch...   - I've got money saying he's still alive.
賭十塊我會先找到     來看這裡有什麼
- 10 bucks says I nail him first.   - Let's see what we've got in here.
你沒希望了     你認為他在這裡面嗎
- You mugs don't stand a chance.   - Do you think he's in here?
繼續找吧     好吧
- Just keep looking.   - Alright.
蓋瑞·艾尼高、班瑞·比諾、麥克·塞裡奧
"Gary lanico", "Ben Rubino", "Mike Cesario"
全都是幾內亞人
...All the Guineas are buying it.
不是這名字     維維裡·維琪，是你的朋友
- Come on, it's not the right name!   - 'Wee Willie Winkie". A buddy of yours.
我們得找到那混蛋
We've got to find this prick.
那混蛋在哪裡
Where's this son of a bitch?
別混在一起，分開一點
Don't mix them up. Keep them in your pile.
怎麼知道哪些是看過的呢
How am I supposed to know who we've got?
萊賓，閉嘴好嗎
Why don't you just shut up, Reiben?
別吵架     你不高興嗎
- Everybody be friends.   - Cranky there, huh?
有優勝者了     你說什麼
- I think I've got a winner.   - What are you talking about?
瑞恩     瑞恩
- "Ryan."   - Ryan?
梅利西，你看     你簡直是天才
- Take a look at that, Mellis.   - You're really a genius.
這是裡恩，是法語名字，知道這是什麼意思嗎
"R-l-E-N-N-E." That's "Rienne" and it's French. Do you know what that means?
一無所獲     什麼比三條大
- It means "nothing".   - What beats three of a kind?
這些人全都來自紐約     你總是發牢騷
- I got shit here, all guys from New York.   - You're always bitching.
要幫忙嗎     我葫蘆
- Do you need a hand?   - I've got a full house.
我贏了，同花順
I've got you beat. Straight flush.
你偷看我的牌，你作弊
You're looking at my cards. You're cheating.
笨得太離譜了，你識字嗎
Fucking unreal, this guy. Can you read that shit?
天啊，你看這可憐的傢伙     大概不能防彈吧
- Jesus, look at this poor bastard!   - I guess they're not bulletproof.
應該不能
I guess not.
這傢伙沒腦袋     跟你的那裡一樣
- I don't like what's between his ears.  - It's like what's between your legs.
你說得沒錯     傑克森，說得沒錯
- We've got to give him that.   - That's not bad for you, Jackson.
我三條     你們幹什麼
- I've got three of a kind.   - What the hell are you doing?
整個空降師都在看著，這可不是撲克牌
The whole goddam Airborne's watching. These aren't poker chips.
好吧     放回去
- Alright.   - Put them back in there.
他不在這裡
He's not here.
也許我們該分頭去找吧
Maybe we should split into groups?
到樹林裡去叫他的名字
Just wander the woods calling his name.
他遲早會聽到的，瑞恩
He's bound to hear us sooner or later. Ryan!
上尉，這也不是辦法
That might be a little hard to do, Captain.
也許本地人見過他，瑞恩，詹姆斯·瑞恩
Maybe the locals have seen him. Ryan, James Ryan?
瑞恩，有人認識101空降師的瑞恩嗎
Ryan! Anybody know Ryan, 101st Airborne? You know Ryan?
是愛阿華州的二等兵瑞恩嗎
Private James Ryan from lowa? Anybody know a Ryan?
瑞恩     阿喬
- James Ryan!   - Hey, Joe!
麥可森不是認識C連的瑞恩嗎
Doesn't Michaelson pal around with a Ryan from C Company?
應該是     帶他過來
- I think so.   - Bring him up.
你認識二等兵瑞恩嗎     你要大聲一點
- You know Private Ryan?   - You have to speak up...
大聲一點，我的耳朵不靈光
You have to speak up, sir! My hearing is not so good!
手榴彈在耳朵邊爆炸，聽力時有時無的
It comes and goes. A grenade went off right by my head.
你認識二等兵瑞恩嗎     誰
- Got it. Do you know Private Ryan?   - Who?
二等兵瑞恩，詹姆斯·瑞恩     吉米·瑞恩
- Private Ryan? James Ryan?   - Jimmy Ryan?
詹姆斯·法蘭西斯·瑞恩
James. James Francis Ryan.
不，是詹姆斯·法蘭西斯·瑞恩
No, no, no. James Francis Ryan.
給我紙筆
Give me a pencil. Something to write on.
快點，鉛筆
Quick, a pencil!
小鉛筆給你
Here you are, a small one.
寫下來，詹姆斯·法蘭西斯·瑞恩，愛阿華州
Write this down: "James Francis Ryan? Iowa?"
你認識他嗎，快看看
"Do you know him?" Read the message! Look!
我當然認識他     知道他在哪裡嗎
- Yeah, of course I know him.   - Does he know where he is?
我們偏離了降落區二十英里
Yeah, we missed our dropzone by about 20 miles
降落的地方好像是布魯維裡什麼的
and ended up way over by "Bumville" or some damn place.
我跟他和其他人正要到這裡集合
Him, me and a couple of others were coming here to the rally point.
卻遇到一位上校正召集弟兄前往蘭姆勒
We ran into a colonel who was gathering up men to go to Ramelle.
蘭姆勒     去防守一座橋
- Ramelle?   - To babysit a bridge.
那是我最後一次看見他     好極了，謝謝你
- That's the last I've seen of him.   - Great! Thank you!
寫謝謝，你看，謝謝     不客氣
- Write "Thank you". Read. Thank you.   - You're welcome!
大家過來
Assemble on me.
謝謝你，中尉
Thank you, Lieutenant.
蘭姆勒
Ramelle.
我們在這裡，蘭姆勒在麥德里特河畔
We're here. There. Ramelle is on the Merderet River,right here.
在我們的西南方
Just to the southwest of us.
你知道那座橋嗎
You know anything about that bridge we just talk about?
知道，瑟堡一直是盟軍的目標
Yeah. The target has always been Cherbourg.
要佔領深水港才能攻佔巴黎，而隆美爾也知道
We can't push on Paris until we take a deep water port and Rommel knows that.
他會試著把裝甲部隊運過麥德里特河
He's going to try to get his armour across the Merderet River anyway he can.
這樣就能在我們進攻瑟堡時夾擊我們
That way he can hit us in the flank when we make the turn for Cherbourg.
所以有橋樑的村莊都成了重要的據點
That makes any village on the river with a bridge solid gold real estate.
走吧
Let's go.
上尉
Captain.
那是什麼
What the hell is that?
廢棄的雷達站
A radar site. It's got to be out of action.
下麵的沙坑裡有敵人
Looks like we've got something in that sandbag bunker under the station.
看到嗎     對，我也這麼想
- See it?   - Yeah, that's my guess, too.
那是什麼     機槍，或許是MG-42
- What is it?   - Machine gun, probably MG-42.
那些人就是被它幹掉的嗎     也許瑞恩也在裡面
- Is that what got those guys?   - Maybe one of them is Ryan.
不，他們是82隊的，你的運氣才沒那麼好
No, their patches are 82nd, so your luck's not that good.
我不知道你們的腳程，但若我們悄悄地繞道
I don't know how fast you are, but if we detour this way quick and quiet,
德軍就不會知道我們在這裡
the Krauts will never even know we were here.
為何不繞道走
What I'm trying to say is why don't we just go around the thing?
我明白，但不能夠這樣
I hear what you're saying, but we can't go around it.
我支持萊賓的說法，避開那些機槍就行了
I'm with Reiben. I mean, we left those 88s.
空軍可不會專程來對付一挺機槍
For the Air Force. They're not going to spend ordnance on one machine gun.
上尉
Captain.
繞路還是能達成任務，這並不是我們的任務，對吧
We can skip it and still accomplish our mission. This isn't our mission, right?
梅利西，你想這樣做嗎
Is that what you want to do, Mellish?
任由其他部隊中伏嗎
Leave it here so they can ambush another company?
不，我只是說這並非我們的目標
No, I'm simply saying it's seems an unnecessary risk given our objective.
我們的目標是打勝仗
Our objective is to win the war.
我有不祥的預感
It's just that I don't have a good feeling about this one.
你什麼時候有過好的預感了
When was the last time you felt good about anything?
好吧，三個人沖前開火
Alright. Three runners with suppressing fire.
梅利西，你跑右邊，我跑中間
Mellish. You hook to the right, I'll go up the middle.
誰跑左邊
Who's going left?
我去
I'll do it.
我跑左邊     好
- I go left.   - Alright.
厄本，跟傑克森對調，而你待在後面
Upham, switch off with Jackson and you linger in the rear.
我們向前猛攻，迫使他換子彈
We advance and keep pressure on him 'til he has to change out his barrels.
然後就扔手榴彈
We should be able to hit them from grenade range.
也許我該跑中間     你那種跑法嗎，不用了
- Maybe I should go up the middle?   - The way you run? I don't think so.
也許我該跑左邊     也許你該閉嘴
- Maybe I should go left,sir.   - Maybe you should shut up!
萊賓，儘管開火
Reiben, base of fire.
把彈藥帶在身邊
Mags and clips where you can reach them
負責主攻的多帶些手榴彈
and extra grenades for the base runners.
山上安全了，幹掉了四個     厄本
- Hill's clear. Four down and dead!   - Upham!
收拾裝備帶上來，我們需要水和藥物
Grab the gear and get up here! We need water and extra dressing.
從藥包裡把嗎啡拿出來
Get the morphine out of the medical kit!
混蛋     撒上磺胺粉
- Son of a bitch!   - Get some sulfa on there.
把我的腿抬高     行了
- Move my legs up.   - I got them.
快倒磺胺粉     聽我說
- Pour sulfa.   - Listen to my voice.
你會沒事的，醫師
You're going to be alright, Doc.
沒事的，很快就能上醫療船
You're fine. You're going on a hospital ship.
倒多一點     把腿抬起
- More sulfa!   - Move my legs up.
把腿抬高     行了
- Put my legs up.   - I've got them.
你會沒事的     沒事，醫生
- You're going to be OK.   - It's alright, Doc.
厄本，把水壺給我     快
- Upham, give me your canteen!   - Come on.
我們會帶你離開的     壓著傷口
- We're going to get you out of here.   - Put some pressure on it.
我中彈了嗎，傷勢怎麼樣     給他注射嗎啡
- Am I shot? How does it look?   - Give him some morphine.
傷勢怎麼樣     你會沒事的
- How does it look?   - You're going to be OK.
要注射嗎啡了
Here comes the morphine.
被射中脊椎了嗎
Am I shot in the spine?
沒事的     是不是射中脊椎
- You're OK.   - Am I shot in the spine?
抬起他     把他翻過去
- Lift him up.   - Move him over.
壓著傷口     輕點
- Put some pressure on.   - Easy, easy.
沒事的，醫生
It's OK, Doc. It's alright.
韋德，子彈穿了出去，你背後有個彈孔
Wade, you've got an exit wound. It's in the small of your back.
那個洞有多大     像橡果那麼大
- How big is the hole?   - It's about the size of an acorn.
好了     放下他
- It's fine.   - Put him back.
壓住傷口
Put some pressure on it. Put some pressure on it.
Put some pressure on it!
用力一點
Put some more pressure on it.
還有更嚴重的傷口嗎
Is there anything bleeding worse than the others?
有，這裡，知道在哪裡嗎，這裡
Yeah, right here. Do you know what it is? Right here.
我把你的手放到上面     我們正壓著傷口
- I'll put your hand on it.   - We got some pressure on there.
就是這裡
That's the one.
天啊，那是我的肝臟
Oh, my God! My liver! It's my liver!
教我們該怎麼救你
Tell us what to do. Tell us how to fix you.
我們該怎麼辦，告訴我們
What can we do? Tell us what to do.
給我一點嗎啡
I could use a little morphine.
多一點嗎啡
More morphine, sir.
好的
OK. OK.
什麼     給他注射
- Sir? What?   - Give it to him.
給他注射
Give it to him.
我不想死     韋德，我們正在注射
- I don't want to die!   - Here you go, Wade. Here it comes.
再注射一劑
Give him another one.
媽媽
Mama...
Mama.
我想回家
I want to go home, I want go home.
媽媽
Mama, Mama, Mama...
Mama, Mama, Mama, Mama...
萊賓，抓住他
Reiben, hold him!
等一下
Not yet!
先叫他替韋德挖個墳墓
First make him mark and cover Wade's body for Grave Detail.
也替那些傘兵挖個墳墓
Same thing for the paratroopers down there.
拿走他的裝備，查問他
Strip that stuff off him. Check him for intelligence.
問這混蛋，韋德是不是他殺的，快問
Ask this piece of shit if he shot Wade! Ask him!
有用嗎     有
- Does it matter?   - It does!
閉上你的臭嘴
Shut up with that filthy pig Latin.
傑克森，你中彈了嗎
Jackson, are you hit?
只是擦傷而已
It just skinned the arm.
把傷口處理好，你和中士留意周圍
Get it cleaned and dressed. You and Sarge watch the perimeter.
他求我們別殺他     厄本，我不管他說什麼
- He says, "Please don't shoot."   - I don't care what he says, Upham.
長官，你要讓他們殺他嗎
Sir? Sir, are you going to let them kill him?
這是不對的     那你去幫他埋屍體
- This is not right, sir.   - You can help him with the bodies.
這是什麼一回事
What is happening?
美國人
American.
我喜歡美國人
I like American.
輪船威裡
Steamboat Willie.
輪船威裡     輪船威裡，美國人
- Steamboat Willie.   - Steamboat Willie. American.
他說他還沒完成     那是你的想法，來吧
- He says he's not finished.   - That's what you think. Come on.
求求你，我喜歡美國人
Please! I like America!
美國什麼都好
Fancy schmancy! What a cinch!
美國什麼都有
Go fly a kite! Cat got your tongue! Cool beans!
貝蒂小姐，好性感
Betty Boop! What a dish.
貝蒂嘉寶，腿很美
Betty Grable. Nice gams.
我說你看到嗎
I say can you see
我說
I say...
去你的希特勒
Fuck Hitler.
Fuck Hitler!
長官，他說他替韋德的死難過
Sir, he says he's sorry about Wade. He says he's sorry about Wade.
上尉
Captain!
上尉，你也知道這樣做不對
Captain, this isn't right. You know this.
他是戰俘，他已經投降了
He's a prisoner. He surrendered. He surrendered, sir!
告訴他
Tell him...
朝那方向走一千步，然後脫掉蒙眼布
to march 1,000 paces in that direction.Then he can take off the blindfold.
向首個遇到的盟軍自首
He turns himself in to the first Allied patrol.
你在說笑嗎，放他走
Are you kidding? We're letting him go?
萊賓，他是戰俘，不能帶著他走
He's a POW, Reiben. We can't take him with us.
我軍自會處置他     算他命大
- Our guys will pick him up.   - That was a close shave.
真幸運
Lucky Strikes.
帶我去看球賽
Take me out to the ball game...
萬一他被敵軍救回，又會回來作戰的
Only if he doesn't get picked up by his own and get thrown back into circulation.
上尉，你白白放過了敵人     簡直白癡
- Captain, you just let the enemy go.   - This is such bullshit.
沒錯     白癡，這是白癡嗎
- You all got that right.   - Bullshit? This is bullshit?
難道可以射殺戰俘嗎，這樣是有違軍法的
Shooting a prisoner is OK? It's against the rules!
軍法跟你的新朋友一起走了
The goddam rules just walked off with your new friend.
上尉，這樣做是對的吧
But I guess that was the decent thing to do, Captain?
收拾東西，出發吧
Get your gear. Let's go.
你們聽到了，收拾東西
You heard him. Gear up.
上尉剛下了命令     是的
- The Captain just gave you an order.   - Yeah.
就像他下令攻下機槍台一樣，真是大英雄
Like the one he gave to take this machine gun. That was a real doozy.
你太過分了
You're out of line!
他命令我們拿下這裡真是英明
That was one hell of a call coming to take this nest,
但我們卻因此喪失了一位隊友
but what the hell, we only lost one of our guys going for it.
瑞恩媽媽一定很高興，知道她兒子的性命
I hope Mama Ryan's really happy knowing that little Jimmy's life
比我們兩位隊友的還重要
was more important than two of our guys!
但我們還沒找到他吧
But then, we haven't found them, have we?
你     放開我
- Hey...   - Get off me!
萊賓，起來
Reiben, get up.
拿起東西，入列
Gear up. Fall in.
我要退出這項任務
I'm done with this mission.
等等
Hey! Hey!
長官     你不能一走了之
- Sir...   - Don't you walk away from your captain!
萊賓，給我回來     不
- Reiben, get back in line!   - No, sir.
我寧可坐牢也不想繼續了
I'll spend the rest of my life in the stockade rather than go on.
我說最後一遍     上尉
- I'm not going to ask you again.   - Captain!
白癡     入列
- This is bullshit!   - Fall in!
你要因為瑞恩而殺我嗎     不，是因為我討厭你
- Are you going to shoot me over Ryan?   - No, because I don't like you.
他想走就讓他走吧
If he wants to go, just let him go!
你不管嗎，上尉，你看到了嗎
Are you letting this happen? Captain! You see this?
上尉，瑞恩已經死了
Captain. Sir, Ryan's dead.
白癡     這裡情況不妙
- Bullshit!   - We have a situation here.
我有很強的第六感
I have a sixth sense. I know it in my bones.
你不殺德軍卻要殺我嗎
We didn't kill the Kraut. Now you're going to shoot me.
他比你好     下手吧
- He's better than you.   - Just do it!
打我的腿     我要打你的大嘴巴
- Put one in my leg...   - I'll shoot you in your big mouth!
廢話少說，開槍吧
Put your money where your mouth is and do it!
你總是那麼多話說
You don't know how to shut up.
上尉，求求你     賭金有多少了
- Captain, please!   - What's the pool on me up to?
你是個懦弱的混蛋     中士，我在等你開槍
- You are a coward son of a bitch!   - I'm waiting, Sarge.
賭金累積到有多少了
What's the pool on me up to right now?
有多少了
What's it up to?
三百塊嗎
What is it? 300 dollars, is that it?
我是個老師
I'm a schoolteacher.
我教英文作文
I teach English Composition...
在賓夕法尼亞州一個叫艾德里的小鎮
in this little town called Addley, Pennsylvania.
這十一年來我在湯瑪斯愛迪生高校任教
In the last 11 years, I've been at Thomas Alva Edison High School.
在春季我是棒球教練
I was the coach of the baseball team in the springtime.
我真該死
I'll be doggone.
我在家鄉告訴人家我的職業時
Back home, when I tell people what I do for a living
他們覺得“一看就知道”
they think, "Well, that figures."
但到了這裡
But over here, it's...
卻成為了一個大秘密
a big, big mystery.
我想我變了一點
So, I guess I've changed some.
有時我想我改變了很多
Sometimes I wonder if I've changed so much
回家後也許妻子會不認得我
my wife is even going to recognise me whenever I get back to her...
或許我不能向她
and how I'll ever be able to...
訴說像今天這種事情
tell her about days like today.
瑞恩
Ryan...
我對瑞恩一無所知，我才不管
I don't know anything about Ryan. I don't care.
他跟我毫無關係，那只是個名字
He means nothing to me, it's just a name,
但要是到蘭姆勒帶他回家
but if going to Ramelle and finding him so he can go home,
能讓我回到妻子身邊
if that earns me the right to get back to my wife, then...
我會接下這項任務
...then that's my mission.
你想退出，重返戰場嗎
You want to leave? You want to go off and fight the war?
沒關係
Alright.
我不會阻止你，我甚至會替你申請
Alright, I won't stop you. I'll even put in the paperwork.
我只知道我多殺一人便離家越遠
I just know that with every man I kill, the farther away from home I feel.
∮ 昔日的回憶湧現 ∮
by memories of days gone by
∮ 孤獨中你嘲弄我 ∮
In my solitude you taunt me
∮ 勾起不死的記憶 ∮
with memories that never die
∮ 我坐在椅上滿懷絕望 ∮
I sit in my chair filled with despair
∮ 比任何人都要哀傷 ∮
There's no one could be so sad
∮ 看著坐著的地方盡是陰霾 ∮
With gloom everywhere I sit and I stare
∮ 我很快就會瘋掉 ∮
I know that I'll soon go mad
有坦克，躲好
Half-track! Cover!
是誰開槍
Who's doing the shooting? Who's doing the shooting?
準備行動，攻擊左邊
Get ready to move. Take their left flank!
小心點，以防有餘兵
Hold on and make sure they're down.
我們是101師，現在出來
101st! We're coming out!
裝甲兵第二師
That was a recon. element, 2nd SS.
我們正在等待情報，一定是他們了
We've been expecting a probe. That must have been it.
第二突擊隊C連米勒上尉
Captain Miller, Charlie Company, 2nd Rangers.
501師E連漢德森下士
Corporal Henderson, Easy Company, 501st.
506團第一隊瑞恩     506團第三隊托恩比
- Ryan, First of 506th.   - Toynbee, Third of 506th.
詹姆斯·法蘭西斯·瑞恩     對，你怎麼會知道
- James Francis Ryan?   - Yes,sir.How did you guess that?
看來敵方攻勢猛烈     對，是小組部隊的進攻
- Looks like you got hit pretty hard.   - Yes,sir.Small unit action.
他們的88毫米炮威力強勁
They came in and beat the hell out of us with 88s.
要是你們就是救兵，我可要投訴
Tell you what. If you're our relief, I'm going to file a complaint.
我不會怪你
I wouldn't blame you.
誰是你的指揮官
Who's your CO?
原本是簡甯斯上尉
It would've been Captain Jennings.
但下士已是這兒的最高級軍官了
I'm afraid the best we can muster up now is a corporal.
那你們為什麼來這裡
So what are you guys all about?
我們為他而來，瑞恩
We're here for him. Ryan.
我
Me, sir?
你是愛阿華州的詹姆斯·法蘭西斯·瑞恩吧
James Francis Ryan of lowa?
對，愛阿華州佩頓市，這是怎麼回事
Yes, sir. Peyton,Iowa, that's correct. What is this about?
你兄長陣亡了
Your brothers were killed in combat.
哪一個
Which ones?
全部
All of them.
真的嗎
On the level?
恐怕是真的
Yeah, I'm afraid so.
大概要一段時間才能接受
You might want to take some time with this.
要是你想到什麼地方
If there's someplace you want to go and...
是怎麼回事     瑞恩的兄弟去世了
- What's this all about?   - Ryan lost his brothers.
哪一個     全部
- Which one?   - All of them.
你們專程跑來告訴我嗎
You came all the way out here to tell me that?
你要回家
You're going home.
我們奉命帶你回去
Our orders are to bring you back.
帶我回去
Bring me back?
下士，我不是想令你人手短缺，但這是命令
Corporal,I don't mean to leave you more short-handed,but orders are orders.
想跟什麼人聯絡嗎
Any communications about when you will be relieved?
我們也不知道南方的情況
We can't tell. We don't know what's happening south of us.
但我的命令不許我擅離職守
My orders don't include me abandoning my post.
我知道，但情況有變
I understand that, but this changes things.
我不認同
I don't see that it does, sir.
這是美軍參謀長的命令
The Chief of Staff for the US Army says it does.
我們奉命死守這座橋
Our orders are to hold this bridge at all costs.
我方戰機已經把麥德里特河的所有橋樑炸斷
Our planes in the 82nd have taken out every bridge across the Merderet,
除了瓦隆尼和這裡兩處
with the exception of two: one at Valognes and this one.
要是給德軍拿下我們就要退守
If the Germans take it, we'll have to displace.
部隊的任務是一回事，但你要離開了
Private.It's one thing that your outfit wants to stay,but your party's over here.
援軍到達前我不能離開
I can't leave before the reinforcements are here.
三分鐘內收拾行裝
You've got three minutes to get your gear.
那他們怎麼辦     混蛋
- What about them,there's barely...   - Hey,asshole!
我們兩位隊友已經為你送命
Two of our guys already died trying to find you.
真的嗎     是的
- Sir?   - That's right.
他們叫什麼名字     艾文·韋德和艾德林·卡帕佐
- What were their names?   - Irwin Wade and Adrian Caparzo.
韋德和誰
Wade and?
卡帕佐
Caparzo.
沒有理由要這樣
It doesn't make any sense.
這樣沒道理，我有什麼資格離開
It doesn't make any sense, sir. Why do I deserve to go?
為什麼不是他們，他們也同樣努力
Why not any of these guys? They all fought just as hard as me.
你死後傳訊員就要跟
Is that what they're supposed to tell your mother
你母親這樣說嗎
when they send her another folded American flag?
跟她說你在這裡找到我
Tell her that when you found me I was here,
我要跟軍中其他兄弟在一起
and I was with the only brothers that I have left,
我怎樣也不會離棄他們
and that there was no way I was going to desert them.
她應該會明白，我不會離開這座橋
I think she'll understand that. There's no way I'm leaving this bridge.
現在怎麼辦
What are your orders?
中士，我們進入了一個奇異的國度
Sergeant, we have crossed some strange boundary here.
一切都異乎尋常
Our world has taken a turn for the surreal.
但問題始終要解決
Clearly, but the question still stands.
我不知道，你覺得怎樣
I don't know. What do you think?
你不會想知道
You don't want to know what I think.
不，我想知道
No, Mike, I do.
我一方面同意他的說法他有什麼資格
Part of me thinks the kid's right. What's he done to deserve this?
他既然想留下來，我們就乾脆回去
If he wants to stay here, fine. Let's leave him and go home.
是的
Yeah.
但我還有一個想法，要是我們也留下來
But another part of me thinks, "What if by some miracle we stay"
會締造什麼奇跡呢
"and actually make it out of here?"
有天我們回想此事
Some day we might look back on this and decide that
也許會覺得在這場混帳戰爭中
saving Private Ryan was the one decent thing we pulled out of
拯救瑞恩是唯一的好事
this whole godawful, shitty mess.
這是我的想法，上尉，如你所言
That's what I was thinking, sir. Like you said, Captain.
我們會留下來一起為團聚戰鬥
We do that, we all earn the right to go home.
兄弟
Oh, brother...
只有這些武器
This is everything.
23毫米機槍、17枚手榴彈、11個霍金斯地雷
You've got the.230 calibre machine guns, 17 grenades, 11 Hawkins mines.
你有兩支火箭筒，但只能發射八次
You've got two bazookas, but they've only got eight rounds left.
還有各式小手槍
And assorted small arms.
本來有60毫米迫擊炮，但已損毀
We had a.60 mortar, but an arty round took it out.
敵軍坦克壓過來我們吐口水攻擊好了
Might as well be spit wads if they roll on us with tanks.
敵軍當然會動用坦克     你有什麼意見
- Which they're sure to do.   - What are you thinking, sir?
我提議進行夾擊
I'm thinking I'm going to whip around the flanks.
要把他們引到大街
Unless we can draw them up the main road between the buildings,
用瓦礫造一個瓶頸
where all the rubble makes a bit of a bottleneck
讓坦克無用武之地嗎     可以的話
- Disable him?   - If we can.
造個六十噸的路障，然後展開夾擊
Make a 60-tonne roadblock. Then we've got a fighting chance at her flanks.
好，分散他們，別讓他們集結
Good. Split them up, don't let them mass.
然後逐一擊破，再退回大橋
Hit them hard one-on-one, and fall back to the bridge.
下麵放一台機槍，另一台置於高處
Machine gun on the move down here, number two up high to piss on them.
計畫就是這樣，傑克森
That would be the idea. Jackson!
可以的話我想你去鐘樓
If we can, I'd like to get you up in that bell tower.
知道     我會給你安排幫手
- Yes, sir.   - I'll give you some company.
也好，還要30毫米狙擊槍和一千發子彈
Some company couldn't hurt. A.30 with about a 1,000 rounds would be OK.
派克，有工作給你
Parker, job opportunity.
這主意不錯
It's not the worst idea ever,
但勝負關鍵在於把坦克弄到街上讓我們夾擊
but everything depends on getting the tank down the road for us to knock out.
你有什麼計畫
How the hell do you plan on doing that?
他說得對，空降師的隊友剛說
He's right. As our colleague from Airborne pointed out
我們有的是口水
what we've got is a bunch of spit wads.
但把坦克引來後怎麼應付
How do we stop the tank if we get it to commit?
先用兔子引它追趕
Give it a rabbit to chase.
接著攻擊坦克的履帶
We could hit the tank in the tracks.
對，但用什麼攻擊
Yeah, but with what?
用粘附式炸彈     粘附式炸彈
- We could try a sticky bomb.   - Sticky bomb, sir?
是你編出來的吧
Sir, are you making that up?
不，你可以去翻翻作戰手冊
No, it's in the field manual. Check it out, if you want to.
手冊不知道在那裡，你儘管講解一下
We seem to be out of field manuals. Perhaps you could enlighten us.
有炸藥吧，黃色炸藥還是B成分炸藥
You have some demolition, don't you? TNT or Composition B?
很多，橋那裡的B炸藥，足以把橋炸斷兩次
Plenty. I've got that bridge wired with enough Composition B to blow it twice.
那拿一點出來
You can spare some, then.
用一隻軍襪裝滿炸藥
You take a standard GI sock, cram it full with Composition B,
再加進導火線，表面塗滿機油
and rig up a simple fuse. Then you coat the whole thing with axle grease.
炸彈扔出就能粘附於目標物
That way, when you throw it, it should stick.
有粘力，所以叫粘附式炸彈
It's a bomb that sticks. It's a sticky bomb.
有更好的方法，儘管說出來
Come up with a better way to knock the tracks off a tank, I'm all ears.
這主意不錯，我們要把襪子奉獻
This is good. Now we have to surrender our socks!
拉上去
Haul away.
選擇攻擊範圍，與鐘樓組成交叉火力網
Select the field of fire. Crossfire with the one in the bell tower.
我負責左方的地區
I can cover 12 to 9 from here.
慢慢來     拿到了
- Easy!   - I've got her!
這是地雷
Here are the mines.
要配置得當才行
For being the best we can do,
前面的機槍位置不太好
that forward machine gun is not in a terrible firing position.
應該放到這裡
And this position right here...
這是最後防線
This is the Alamo.
要是退到這裡，最後一個活人負責炸橋
They push us this far, the last man alive blows the bridge.
導火線能燒三十秒，告訴大家
We've only got a 30-second delay on the fuse, so tell everyone
點火後快逃，不然性命不保
that if you're last you'd better hurry or you'll not live long.
上尉，我有什麼任務
Captain? Where am I during all this?
留在我兩英尺之內，不許有異議
Never more than two feet away from me. And that's not negotiable.
跟我去拿彈藥
I'm going to get some ammo. Come on.
厄本，聽著     是的
- Hey, Upham, listen to me.   - Yes.
你在聽嗎     是的
- Are you listening?   - Yes.
我們會不斷東奔西跑
We're going to be displacing and falling back like crazy sons of bitches,
你要運送彈藥，隨傳隨到，不然我們就死定
so you've got to be Johnny-on-the-spot with the ammo,or we're dead.
你明白嗎     隨傳隨到
- Do you understand?   - Johnny-on-the-spot.
你沒事吧     沒事
- Yeah. Are you alright?   - Yeah.
我們從英國出發時也會分發香煙
When we shipped out of England we got cigarettes
我卻說“謝謝，我不抽煙”
and I said, "No, thank you. I don't smoke."
形勢很兇險吧     難以置信
- Quite a situation, huh?   - Unbelievable.
這差事混帳得不得了
Yeah. "Fucked-Up Beyond All Recognition", right?
沒錯
You've got that right.
“苦差”     是的
- "FUBAR"!   - Alright!
很痛
Ouch.
這可不是玩的
Yeah, well... It's going to be a real show, huh?
知道了
Yeah, OK.
放輕鬆
Take it easy.
“苦差”
"FUBAR."
是誰的歌聲
Who's that singing, sir?
艾迪斯·皮雅福
Edith Piaf.
她為什麼這麼傷心
What is she so upset about?
情人離異，但她的面容歷歷在目
Her lover left her, but she still sees his face everywhere she goes.
就是這樣
That would do it.
∮ 生命中就只有你 ∮
"Even life itself only represents you."
∮ 夢著你擁我入懷 ∮
"Sometimes I dream that I'm in your arms."
那是什麼，她曾經唱過     是副歌
- What was that? She sang it before.   - The chorus.
副歌
The chorus.
∮ 每當你耳語喃喃 ∮
"And you speak softly in my ear."
∮ 都讓我閉目靜聽 ∮
"And you say things that make my eyes close."
∮ 感覺美妙 ∮
"And I find that marvellous."
厄本
Again, Upham...
老實說，你使我莫名的興奮
...to be honest, I find myself curiously aroused by you.
棒極了
Marvellous.
這首歌很哀傷，開始時她唱著
It's a really melancholy song. At the beginning of the song she says:
∮ 你離去後，我就傷心絕望 ∮
"And then one day you left me and I've been desperate ever since."
∮ 漫天滿地，都是你的影子 ∮
"I see you all over the sky, I see you all over the earth."
再聽多幾首這種歌不用德軍開槍
Any more songs like this, the Krauts won't have to shoot me.
我就割脈自殺了
I'm just going to slit my own wrists.
厄本，你好奇怪
You're a strange bird, Upham.
對不起，是艾迪斯
I'm sorry. It's Edith, you know.
知道這首歌讓我想起什麼嗎
You know what that song reminds me of?
瑞雪太太在我出發前的一番話
Mrs. Rachel Troubowitz and what she said when I left for Basic.
說什麼     她說“別碰我”
- What?   - "Don't touch me?"
不，她是公寓管理員的妻子
No. She's our Super's wife.
她到我媽的店買衣服，胸圍有44EE
She comes into my mum's shop to try a few things. She's like a 44 Double E.
EE     好大呢
- Double E?   - They're massive.
是一對大胸脯
Those are big titties.
我騙她穿42D的衣服，我們在更衣室裡
I've got her convinced that she's a 42 D. So we're in the dressing room
她嘗試擠進那件絲帶束腰
and she tries to get into this side-cut,silk-ribboned,triple-panel girdle
還有神奇胸罩
with the shelf-lift brassiere.
很好看，都擠了出來
It's beautiful. She's pouring out of this thing.
很緊嗎     不，很美
- Is it tight?   - No, it's beautiful.
她看得出我的小弟像自由神像般又大又硬
She sees me and can tell I've got a hard-on the size of the Statue of Liberty.
於是她叫我冷靜
She says, "Richard, calm down", and she says,
又說要是在戰場上難過害怕
"Over there, if you see anything that upsets you, if you're scared,"
就閉眼想想它們
"I want you to close your eyes and think of these, you understand?"
我說我明白了
So I said, "Yes, ma'am."
你沒事吧
Are you alright, sir?
我在數拍子
Yeah, I'm just keeping the rhythm.
你在老家真的是老師嗎
Is it true you were a teacher back home?
是的     我是當不上老師的了
- Yes.   - That's something I could never do.
我家兄弟都不聽老師的話
Not with the way me and my brothers treated our teachers. No, sir!
我教過上千個你這樣的孩子
I had a thousand kids like you.
我想不起哥哥的樣貌
I can't see my brothers' faces.
怎樣努力也想不起來，你試過這樣嗎
I've been trying and I can't see their faces at all. Has that happened to you?
你要想想發生過的事
You've got to think of a context.
那是什麼意思
What does that mean?
不能只想他們的樣子，要想些具體事情
You don't just think about their faces, you think about something specific,
你們的共同經歷
something you've done together.
我想家的時候想得很具體
When I want to think of home, I think of something specific.
我想起後院的吊床
I think of my hammock in the backyard
或者是妻子戴起我的舊手套修剪玫瑰花叢
or my wife pruning the rose bushes in a pair of my old work gloves.
有一晚兩個哥哥把我弄醒
This one night, two of my brothers woke me up in the middle of the night.
說要給我驚喜
They said they had a surprise for me.
他們帶我到穀倉的閣樓
They took me to the barn up into the loft
原來大哥丹尼
and there was my oldest brother Dan
跟愛莉絲·賈汀在裡面
with Alice Jardine!
想像一下，那女孩從樹上掉下來
Picture a girl who just took a nosedive from the ugly tree
會讓所有樹枝都給壓斷
and hit every branch coming down!
丹尼脫去她的襯衫
And Dan's got her shirt off...
接著要把胸罩也脫下時肖恩突然大叫
So he's trying to get her bra off and all of a sudden Sean screams out
“丹尼，你年紀還小，不可以這樣”
"Danny, you're a young man. Don't do it!"
愛莉絲·賈汀馬上大叫，跳了起來
Alice Jardine hears this and she screams and jumps up
想沖出去，但她的頭給襯衫蒙著
and tries to run out, but she's got her shirt over her head.
所以撞到牆壁，暈了過去
She runs into the wall and knocks herself out.
丹尼很生氣，追著我們
Now Dan is so mad at us. He starts coming after us,
但愛莉絲暈倒了，他要弄醒她
but at the same time Alice is unconscious. He's got to wake her up.
於是一手抓著她的腿猛拉
He grabs her by a leg and drags her
一手拿著鏟子追趕肖恩
and at the same time he picks up a shovel and goes after Sean!
肖恩說“你幹嘛打我，我是在幫你”
And Sean says, "Why are you trying to hit me? I just did you a favour!"
丹尼更加生氣，亂揮鏟子
This makes Dan more angry. He tries to swing this thing.
最後鏟子脫手，打破了火油燈
He loses his shovel. It goes out of his grasp and hits a kerosene lantern.
爆炸著火，穀倉幾乎給燒掉
The thing explodes. The whole barn almost goes up because of this thing.
這就是最後一晚，丹第二天就上戰場去
That was it, that was the last... Dan went off to Basic the next day.
這是四兄弟最後一次共聚
That was the last night the four of us were together.
已經過了兩年
That was two years ago.
天啊
Oh, my.
再說說妻子和玫瑰花叢的事
Tell me about your wife and those rose bushes.
不，那些事要留給自己
No. No, that one I save just for me.
敵人從東面開來
Enemy from the east.
兩倆虎式坦克，兩輛裝甲車
He sees two Tiger tanks, two Panzer tanks.
五十人以上的步兵隊伍
Infantry. 50 plus change.
分散，各就各位，萊賓，去當兔子
Disperse! You know what to do. Reiben, get on the rabbit.
厄本，躲起來     梅利西、漢德森，準備開火
- Upham, get some cover.   - Mellish and Henderson, lock and load!
大家檢查武器
Everybody check your ammo!
萊賓，祝你好運     不用祝福，我生來幸運
- Good luck,Reiben!   - I don't need any luck,I was born lucky!
拿著五枚曳光彈     知道，照亮兩端
- One in five tracer.   - Yes, and tracers point both ways.
去檢查頂端的空間
Why don't you check the head space and she should run.
厄本，快點
Upham, hustle up!
厄本下士，這裡沒有30毫米口徑機槍
Corporal Upham. We don't have a.30 calibre machine gun here.
梅利西和鐘樓的傑克森才需要這個
Either Mister Mellish or Mr Jackson in the bell tower needs that.
厄本，傑克森有子彈，去拿給梅利西
Upham! Jackson's fine, turn around to Mellish!
有很多步兵，不知道會否上釣
There's a ton of infantry. I don't know if they took the bait, though.
還有口香糖嗎
Have you got any more of that?
裝甲車沒有上當
The Panzers didn't take the bait.
步兵團正向左進發
The infantry's moving to the left.
一輛裝甲車跟二十人剛剛開過
A half-track just went by with about 20 troops.
梅利西、漢德森，移位
Mellish, Henderson! Displace!
點火
Do it, now! Light it up! You! Light it!
右邊有三十人，設法阻截他們
30 infantry on the right flank. Get over there, find a hole and stop them!
移位
Displace!
厄本
Upham!
目標清除     去吧
- Clear! OK,   - Go!
德國人
Krauts!
向右邊進攻
Right flank!
伏下
Get down, get down!
厄本，30毫米口徑子彈
Upham! Thirty cal, hurry!
告訴上尉左翼快失守
Find the Captain, this flank's going to fold!
車子還在動
Traversing! He's still in this fight!
瑞恩，伏下
No! Ryan, get down, get down!
瑞恩
Ryan!
閉嘴     放開我
- Keep your mouth.   - Shut Get off me!
你沒事吧     放開我
- Are you alright?   - Get off of me!
上尉，我也沒事，謝謝
I'm fine too, Captain. Thanks.
夾擊他們，扔手榴彈過去
Hit them from both sides. Get aboard! Get a grenade in there!
手榴彈
Grenade!
是20毫米口徑機槍
20 mill! 20 mill!
是重型機槍，幹掉它
Flak gun, 20 mm. Take it out!
機槍給覆蓋著，打不到
Heavy weapon in defilade below! I ain't got a shot!
鉗子隊形，派克，目標在八點鐘方向
Pincer move! Parker! Targets eight o'clock, low!
願天主賜我力量
God grant me strength.
去吧，快移位
Let's go, displace! Come on!
厄本，躲好
Cover! Upham, cover!
30毫米子彈用光了
I'm out of.30 calibre.
天主賜我力量，教我的手打仗
Blessed be the Lord my strength, which teaches my hands to war
教我的指頭作戰
and my fingers to fight.
天主是我的堡壘、我的高塔和解脫者
My goodness and my fortress. My high tower and deliverer.
我的盾牌、我的依靠
My shield and He in whom I trust.
去吧，寶貝
Here you go, baby.
派克，伏下
Parker, get down!
上尉，那20毫米口徑手槍真要命
Captain, that 20 mm is killing us.
一定要毀掉它     我到上面去
- We've got to try to flank it somehow.   - Let me get over there for a top shot.
厄本
Upham!
厄本，拿子彈來
Upham, Upham! Upham, ammo, goddammit!
卡住了，拿30毫米子彈給我     用光了
- I'm jammed! Got any.30 calibre?   - I'm out.
厄本
Upham. Upham!
萊賓
Reiben!
用光了，有人有子彈嗎
I'm out! I need another bandolier. Anybody got a bandolier?
混蛋
You piece of shit!
住手，聽我說，別這樣
Let's stop, let's stop! Listen to me! Stop! No, no, no...
該死
Fuck!
混蛋
Son of a bitch, son of a bitch!
Son of a bitch!
用光了，那些60毫米炮彈
I'm out! Those.60 rounds...
沒有炮管也可以用     怎樣用
- We can use them without the tube.   - How?
這是引爆線，扔出去就行了
Fuse-arming wire, set back and heave it!
德國人
Panzer schreck!
去吧
Go, go!
到最後防線去
We're going to the Alamo.
最後防線
Alamo! Alamo!
交給我們，你們撤退     你跟著來
- We'll take it. You fall back!   - You be right behind us!
我們很快回來
As soon as we're in business.
萊賓，移位
Displace. Reiben!
裝彈
Reload!
開炮
Alright, go!
要炸橋了，快逃     快離開
- We're blowing the bridge! Get off!   - Off the bridge!
中士，麥克，你沒事吧
Sarge! Mike, are you alright?
我被風吹倒了     走吧
- I just got the wind knocked out of me.   - Let's go!
躲好，要炸橋了
Take cover, we're going to blow this bridge!
來吧
Come on!
虎式坦克要過橋了
Tiger company's coming across the bridge.
上尉，找個地方躲好
Captain, get behind something!
麥克
Mike!
上尉，你去哪裡，回來
Captain, where the hell are you going? Captain, get back here!
厄本
Upham!
堅持住
Hang in there.
救護員
Medic!
有救護員嗎
Medic! We've got a medic?
是P-51反坦克攻擊機
They're tankbusters, sir. P-51s.
我們的守護天使
Angels on our shoulders.
什麼事
What, sir?
詹姆斯
James...
別辜負
Earn this.
別辜負大家
Earn it.
“親愛的瑞恩太太”
"My dear Mrs Ryan."
“我有個喜訊要帶給你”
"It's with a profound sense of joy that I write to inform you"
“就是令郞二等兵詹姆斯·瑞恩安然無恙”
"that your son, Private James Ryan, is well"
“現在正從歐洲的戰線回國”
"and at this moment on his way home from European battlefields."
“詹姆斯盡忠職守”
"Reports indicate that James did his duty in combat"
“勇氣過人、堅毅不屈”
"with great courage and steadfast dedication"
“縱使他得知兄弟陣亡”
"even after he was informed of the loss your family has suffered"
“仍堅持參與這場剷除獨裁暴政的偉大戰爭”
"in this great campaign to rid the world of tyranny and oppression."
“我與戰爭部長”
"I take great pleasure injoining the Secretary of War"
“美軍同仁及美國國民”
"the men and women of the US Army, and the citizens of a grateful nation"
“僅此祝你身體健康，與詹姆斯一起活得愉快”
"in wishing you good health and many years of happiness with James."
“雖然愛子平安歸國”
"Nothing, not even the safe return of a beloved son"
“也無法彌補你和千千萬萬個美國家庭”
"can compensate you or the thousands of other American families"
“在戰爭中遭受的創痛”
"who have suffered great loss in this tragic war."
“我想與你分享”
"I might share with you some words"
“一番在悲痛絕望中支援著我的說話”
"which have sustained me through nights of peril, loss and heartache"
“是這樣的一番說話”
"and I quote, 'I pray that our heavenly Father"
“願天主安撫你的喪子之痛”
"may assuage the anguish of your bereavement"
“讓你永遠懷念遠去的摯愛”
"and leave you only the cherished memory of the loved and lost"
“神聖的榮耀都歸於你們”
"and the solemn pride that must be yours"
“因你們為自由付出了重大的代價”
"to have laid a so costly a sacrifice upon the altar of freedom."
“林肯敬上”
"Abraham Lincoln."
“深表敬意”
"Yours very sincerely and respectfully"
“參謀長馬歇爾上將”
"George C. Marshall. General, Chief of Staff."
今天我家人也來了，他們想跟我來
My family is with me today. They wanted to come with me.
說真的，我不知道到這裡來會有什麼感受
To be honest with you, I wasn't sure how I would feel coming back here.
我每天都想著當日你在橋上說的話
Every day, I think about what you said to me that day on the bridge.
我努力活好每一天
I've tried to live my life the best I could.
希望這已經足夠
I hope that was enough.
希望這至少讓你覺得
I hope that at least in your eyes...
我沒有辜負你們為我做的一切
l've earned what all of you have done for me.
詹姆斯
James.
“約翰米勒上尉”
"Captain John H. Miller."
跟我說我這輩子沒白活     什麼
- Tell me I have led a good life.   - What?
跟我說，我是個好人
Tell me I'm a good mess.
你是個好人
You are.
（約翰米勒上尉）
（第二突擊隊）
（死於1944年6月13日）
特效字幕：BeAst製作組  修正：101eagle
導　演
斯蒂文·斯皮爾伯格
編　劇
羅伯特·羅達特
制　片
斯蒂文·斯皮爾伯格
與 伊安·布萊斯
制　片
馬克·戈登
與 加里·萊文森
攝影導演
賈努茲·卡明斯基
藝術指導
湯姆·桑德斯
剪　輯
邁克爾·卡恩
音　樂
約翰·威廉姆斯
服裝設計
瓊安娜·約翰斯頓
聯合制片
邦尼·柯帝士
阿麗森·里昂·賽根
選角導演
鄧尼斯·查米安
湯姆·漢克斯
愛德華·伯恩斯
湯姆·塞茲摩爾
傑瑞米·大衛斯
範·迪塞爾
亞當·戈德堡
巴里·佩珀
吉奧瓦尼·瑞比西
馬特·達蒙
鄧尼斯·法裡納
特德·丹森
哈威·普雷斯內
布萊恩·科蘭斯頓
大衛·沃爾
南森·菲利安
保羅·吉亞瑪提
瑞恩·赫斯特
麥克斯米利安·馬蒂尼
利蘭·奧澤